In 1926, Robert Goddard launched and then crashed
1926年  罗伯特·戈达德设计的火箭在发射后炸了
the world's first liquid propellant rocket.
这是世界上第一个液体推进剂火箭
Its weird design falling afoul of the pendulum rocket fallacy.
其怪异的设计落入了“钟摆式火箭”的谬误
Intuitively, it makes sense to put your engines up top.
从直觉上讲  把引擎放在顶部是很合理的
If i hold this rocket from its bottom, then it just falls over;
如果我在底部托着火箭  它很难立得稳
but pulling from the top like a pendulum
但是在顶部像钟摆一样挂着
this one is able to stay stable.
这个就能保持稳定了
Likewise, during flght, we'd expect that
在飞行时  我们自然也期望
this heavy fuel section keeps the rocket pointing upward.
能靠沉重的油箱作为摆锤  来保持火箭朝上
This doesn't work.
然并卵
I'm about to drop this 5 kilogram medicine ball and half kilo volleyball.
我要丢下这个10斤的健身球和1斤的排球
although the medicine ball is experiencing greater weight force
尽管健身球所受的重力大得多
it also takes more force to move.
但它的惯性也更大
These factors cancel out and both balls land at the same time.
这两个因素相互抵消  导致两个球会同时落地
Since the sections experience the same gravitational acceleration,
由于上下两部分的重力加速度相同
weight alone can't write our structure.
因而没法单靠重力来改变其结构
This isn't true in a pendulum
而钟摆之所以能改变形态
since the pivot is pinned in place.
是因为上面的转轴已经钉死位置了
The only way to change orientation is
火箭想改变方向只有一种方法
with a sideways force providing rotational torque,
就是给火箭一个侧向力  提供旋转扭矩
but since the engines are fixed in position,
但把引擎固定挂在上面的话
no torque can be generated.
就无法产生扭矩了
喜欢这类火箭的人  给火箭加上尾翼吧